Contact

9713082832 (Mobile) mahendrachouhan01@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ mahendrachouhan01 (LinkedIn) github.com/Mahendra-Chouhan (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Python
Artificial Intelligence
Machine Learning

Languages

Hindi (Professional Working)
English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Sequence Models for Time Series and Natural Language Processing Database Administrator Applied Machine Learning in Python Java Advanced SQL Certified

Mahendra Singh Chouhan

Senior Data Scientist at YASH Technologies Indore

Summary

I'm an aspiring Data Scientist with 4+ years of experience work in NLP, NLU, NLG, computer vision. I have been deeply passionate and enthusiastic about the field of Machine learning, Data Science, and Artificial Intelligence I have undertaken several MOOCs, which involved rigorous self-study, in and related to the aforementioned fields.

I have experience in end to end delivery of Machine learning project in Production level. Worked on various problem in BFSI, Retail, telecom and Healthcare Domain. Always ready to learn.

Life Motto: Stay hungry stay foolish

Experience

YASH Technologies Senior Data Scientist March 2020 - Present (6 months) Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India

Wipro Limited
Data Scientist
July 2019 - February 2020 (8 months)
Noida Area, India

- Analysis Images provided by client and create segment images based on type.
- Create unsupervised ML model i.e. Para2Vec model for All Document.
- Create End to End Hierarchy text classification for document types and sub types.
- Create NER models for custom entities for each documents types and sub types.
- Create Restful API for Classification and NER models.
- Create Kafka cluster for real streamline processes.

Page 1 of 3

Tools: TensorFlow, Pandas, Gensim, Sklearn, Kafka, Python, Flask, Docker.

NorthOut

Data Scientist

December 2016 - June 2019 (2 years 7 months)

Indore Area, India

Selecting features, building and optimizing classifiers using machine learning techniques

Data mining using state-of-the-art methods

Extending company's data with third party sources of information when needed Enhancing data collection procedures to include information that is relevant for building analytic systems

Processing, cleansing, and verifying the integrity of data used for analysis

Doing ad-hoc analysis and presenting results in a clear manner

Creating automated anomaly detection systems and constant tracking of its

performance

Myraa Technologies

Data Science Intern

November 2016 - December 2016 (2 months)

- Used Python to implement the Machine Learning algorithm, also using NLP techniques like sequence matching, Bigrams, Jaccard similarity index etc., as well as using the graph database Neo4j.

Also Collaboratively support on designing and engineering an intelligent PDF parser which took financial statements in PDF format as input, and outputted a JSON formatted version to be used

- Using machine learning, developed an algorithm to distinguish between types and sub types of Metal Industry
- Gained skill and experience to incorporate multiprocessing into a software product.
- Developed several valuable skills on collaborating with a team to engineer a software product, using version control softwares like git.

Hiring Hour

Data Science Intern

April 2016 - October 2016 (7 months)

Indore

- Identify trends in various parts of the business based on detailed review and compilation of data.
- Collect and organize pieces of information into meaningful and actionable insights using visual design and infographics that enhances effective decision making.
- Prepare presentation materials to aid in the communication of HR projects, analyses, etc.
- Ensure accuracy and data integrity of HR system.
- Practice independent thinking in managing work and projects.
- Perform research tasks with a view to gather data pertaining to industry, company and customer trends.

Ziolite

Software Engineer January 2012 - April 2016 (4 years 4 months)

Indore Area, India

Website Development, Database management, UI/ UX development, Google analytics analysis, Brand development, Website traffic growth, Developed brand strategy and statistics systems.

freelancer

Freelance

August 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 5 months)

Indore Area, India

work as freelancer

Education

Rajiv Gandhi Prodyogiki Vishwavidyalaya
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science · (2006 - 2010)

University Innovative School,indore Higher Secondary, Mathematics · (2004 - 2006)